It is the greatest mystery of all because no human being will ever solve it.
The Omen is a horror, thriller film directed by Richard Donner.
Immediately after their miscarriage, the US diplomat Robert Thorn adopts
the newborn Damien without the knowledge of his wife.
Yet what he doesn’t know is that their new son is the son of the devil.
Robert Thorn, played by Gregory Peck.
Katherine Thorn, played by Lee Remick.
Keith Jennings, played by David Warner.
Mrs. Baylock, played by Billie Whitelaw.
Damien Thorn, played by Harvey Stephens.
Father Brennan, played by Patrick Troughton.
The Omen is a 1976 supernatural horror film directed by
Richard Donner and written by David Seltzer.
An international co-production of the United Kingdom and the United States, it stars Gregory Peck, Lee Remick, David Warner,
Harvey Spencer Stephens (in his film debut), Billie Whitelaw, Patrick Troughton, Martin Benson, and Leo McKern.
The film's plot follows Damien Thorn, a young child replaced at birth by his father,
unbeknownst to his wife, after their biological child dies shortly after birth.
As a series of mysterious events and violent deaths occur around the family and Damien
enters childhood, they come to learn he is in fact the prophesied Antichrist.
Released theatrically by 20th Century-Fox in June 1976, The Omen received mixed reviews from
critics but was a commercial success, grossing over $60 million at the U.S.
box office and becoming one of the highest-grossing films of 1976.
Retrospective reviews of the film have been more favorable, and the film earned two
Oscar nominations, including a win for Jerry Goldsmith's musical score.
The film spawned the Omen franchise, with Damien – Omen II released two years later, followed by The Final
Conflict (1981) and Omen IV: The Awakening (1991), as well as a 2006 remake and 2024 prequel.
It also spawned a 2016 television series that ran for one season on A&E.
The film explores themes of ambassador, prophecy, monk, photography, nanny.
The tone is dark and intense.